## Majidul Mooktadeer

•914-454-0222• mmookta1@binghamton.edu • https://bit.ly/2HeWxNo

### **SUMMARY**

Full stack software test engineer with over five years of experience in testing various client/server-based application projects. Able to utilize indepth knowledge of process instrumentation, technology integration, and expertise in different aspects of projects to further improve process efficiency. Searching for challenges and opportunities to enhance armamentarium to achieve higher efficiency in automation.

### **OBJECTIVE OF PROJECTS COMPLETED**

- **Project 1**: HealthPlanOne is a health insurance company focused on optimizing consumer health insurance interactions and specializes providing custom sales, marketing, and solutions exclusively for the health insurance industry. This project followed an agile environment, and the QAs were responsible to conduct tests before pre-production to ensure clients satisfaction and to reduce time of personal manual testing execution by implementing Selenium/BDD framework.
- **Project 2**: KeyBank, is one of the nation's largest financial companies. Key's list of services includes commercial banking, investment management, investment banking, and consumer finance to domestic as well as international clients. The project's goal was to deliver high quality products by using the existing framework to review account activity and view credit card statements.
- **Project 3**: The Zebra is an automobile and a home insurance comparison platform that streamlines the shopping experience and empowers consumers to compare quotes regularly. The Zebra produces millions of quotes being one of the nation top leading car and home insurance comparison sites. With this capacity of users, a smooth hassle-free experience is necessary. The goal was to ensure a streamlined navigation for users to create quotes that were free from bugs. This was achieved using implemented frameworks, with the addition of testing on various platforms using Sauce Labs.
- **Project 4:** Virgin America Inc. was a company specializing in airlines and delivery at a low cost. By working in the environment, the team conducted daily regression tests and end-to-end tests to verify that the platform is family-friendly, easy to navigate, and an overall hassle-free experience within the medical devices was working as expected.

### **EXPERIENCE**

### HealthPlanOne | Trumbull, CT

July 2020 - July 2022

 $Sr.\ Software\ Quality\ Assurance\ Web\ \&\ Mobile\ Automation\ Engineer$ 

- Applied extensive knowledge of mobile automation following a 90/10 automation to manual ratio
- Participated in daily scrum calls and updated the team with current test status
- Used Appium to run mobile automation tests on local machine for both iOS simulators and Android emulators using testing frameworks XCUITest and UiAutomator2, respectively
- · Tested on Browser Stack cloud for parallel test execution on different Android and iOS real devices
- Conducted parallel automated iOS and Android tests via Appium on Kobiton server
- Participated in daily standup meetings with the scrum team and followed the agile process implementing 2-week sprints and monthly releases. Relied on Jira to track the agile workflow
- Conducted data-driven testing using TestNG data-provider tag and supplied the JSON objects as data for browser UI automation
- Implemented Maven for build tool
- Utilized WebDriver iO for Mobile Test Automation
- Developed and maintained Page Object Model as part of modular framework using JAVA programming language
- Performed Bug Tracking & Bug Reproducing using Jira
- Coordinated with the development team and the product manager using slack and provided feedback about testing tools, costs, and risk management. Additionally, provided mobile test case status reports and reported all issues promptly.

Sr. Software Quality Assurance Web Automation Engineer

- Worked on web and mobile applications as well as did API testing
- Utilized Espresso framework and UIAutomator2 for real device testing on Android platforms
- Extensive iOS testing both internal and customer-facing application via XCode and XCUITest framework
- Worked in a highly dynamic AGILE environment and participated in scrum and sprint planning meetings.
- Developed and maintained Page Object Model as part of modular framework using JAVA programming language with the help of Selenium WebDriver.
- Written and executed test scripts using IntelliJ IDE.
- Used Firebug and Firepath to identify and locate elements as needed, along with creating custom Xpath using xml functions.
- Used MySQL Server and prepared SQL queries to perform database testing.
- Implemented Maven for build management and implemented CI tool via Jenkins.
- Used Sauce labs to execute Selenium automation suites on different platforms; performed cross browser testing combinations in parallel.
- Implemented Appium Scripts to test iOS and Android platforms.
- Wrote test scenarios on cucumber feature file
- Applied Allure to view detailed test execution reports.
- Used Appium to test key mobile features
- Implemented GitHub for source control.
- Performed Defect Tracking & Management in JIRA. Generated automated daily reports using JIRA API.

#### TheZebra | Austin, TX

**November 2017 - March 2019** 

Sr. Software Quality Assurance Web Automation Engineer

- Following the SDLC process, use requirements documents to create testing strategy including providing test estimates, documenting test plans and objectives, assessing and identifying testing risks, and developing test scenarios and test cases.
- Develop, document, and maintain test artifacts like test data, data validation and automated test scripts using Selenium WebDriver, primary language used for automation was JAVA.
- Assisted on developing and maintaining robust and effective Page Object Model Framework
- Implemented Maven for build management and implemented CI tool Jenkins.
- Applied Allure to view detailed test execution reports.
- Written proficient Java glue code step definitions for test scenario using regex
- Used Appium to test iOS native app on local Appium server along with extensive real device testing on AWS Device Farm cloud service
- Implemented GitHub for source control.
- Executed full test on every regression build and provided detailed report to the upper management
- · Modified test scripts to handle all checked and unchecked exceptions which helped run test smoothly
- Used Maven as primary build management tools
- Used REST Assured to perform automated API testing

### Virgin America Inc.| Burlingame, CA

June 2017 - August 2017

Intern

- Extensive functional testing, developing software testing process, testing scenarios and test plans
- Developed Test Scenarios and Test Cases for large-scale data validation and comparison between two web applications and between the UI and Database defining simple to complex scenarios
- Guided through process and developed test plan documents, strategy, test cases skills using JIRA.
- Performed Functional testing on different web platforms.
- Worked with automation team and learned to help them run Selenium test suites as part of regression testing.
- Identified system problems and contributed to web browser application testing. Reduced time of personal manual testing execution up to 40% utilizing automation for highly repetitive test cases using Selenium.

# **EDUCATION**

Binghamton University, SUNY | Thomas J. Watson College of Engineering and Applied Science

Expected May 2023

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

Major GPA: 3.80/4.00 | Overall GPA: 3.80/4.00